[engine revs]
[Jerry] This is a 1967 Austin-Healey 3000
in ice blue.
It has a straight-six,
150-horsepower engine.
This is a car if you wanna say,
"I really love British sports cars.
"And damn it, I will go down
with that ship if I have to."
-Hello?
-Ricky?
-Who's that?
-Jerry.
[Ricky] Hello, man.
-How's it going?
-[Jerry] What are you doing?
[Ricky] Oh. Sitting out, I think I've got
irritable bowel syndrome.
[Jerry] Oh, God, that is irritating.
[Ricky laughs] Yeah.
-[Jerry] You wanna grab a coffee?
-Yeah.
I'm Jerry Seinfeld, and this is
Comedians in Cars Getting Coffee.
Today my guest is my good friend
Ricky Gervais.
He's a very funny, silly,
English comedian guy.
[laughs]
[Jerry]
And he's just funny. He makes me laugh.
-What do you think?
-[Ricky] It's great.
-English.
-Is it?
-I don't know anything.
-You don't know anything about cars?
-No.
-Is this the seat belt?
-What do you think so far?
-I think it's a death trap.
-It is.
There's no way there's a little air bag
in there, is there?
-There is, but you have to blow it up.
-[laughing]
Quick, we're gonna crash.
Right.
Well, I'm a very nervous passenger,
so let's...
-Did you eat?
-I had some cereal.
-That's so sweet.
-What?
What kind of cereal?
We can't be running out
of stuff to talk about already.
If we're going into detail on the cereal,
we're struggling.
There's a dancing traffic cop.
He's dancing, he's really
having a good time.
She's dancing, too.
We're in the middle of Fame.
Irene Cara.
She did the song, didn't she?
Yes, Fame.
I'm gonna live forever.
-I'm gonna learn how to fly.
-Yeah.
People are gonna see me and die.
Well, who's gonna pay for that?
I think they meant it in a sort of...
-I saw Irene Cara, I died.
-Ah, I see.
-Yeah, exactly.
-In a more like this way.
-I died.
-Yeah.
-I see.
Look at this guy.
Nobody can explain
why the homeless have such fabulous hair.
I love how you start
with "no one can explain."
Like scientists have been working
around the clock for the last 25 years.
They've spent billions
of government dollars,
but they've not come up with anything.
Like, who commissioned
this scientific study?
Okay, here we go.
[engine revving]
No, be sensible.
[Jerry] Oh, Jerry.
Jesus.
Sorry,
are we in The Italian Job?
Why are we doing this?
Oh, no, that made it worse. You--
Jerry! For [bleep] sake!
We're going 70 miles an hour.
We're not going 70.
[Ricky] Let's take the bus.
[Jerry] Oh, Jerry.
Oh, God.
Jerry, why is it so funny
to frighten a grown man?
Fear is funny.
-Fear is funny, yeah.
-Especially when it's not fake.
We're so used to fake fear.
Everyone always acts scared,
-pretends their scared.
-This is real, don't worry about it.
I'm in a tin bucket with no suspension.
Oh, Jesus.
When was the last time
you were this scared?
Doing award shows
and potentially ending my career is my...
That's my adrenaline rush.
I work for the Golden Globe committee.
And this entire thing is a ruse
to get you to do the show again next year.
Yeah.
And I'm just gonna keep driving you
in this terrifying car until you agree.
Oh, God.
I think the first couple,
they were sort of...
They were taken aback.
"Why is this Brit saying
all these awful things to us?"
And then by the third one,
they go, "He's telling jokes. I get it."
What was the introduction for Mel Gibson?
"I like a drink as much as the next man.
"Unless the next man is Mel Gibson."
That's a great joke.
I like a joke that
sneaks up on you like that.
Yeah. Oh, Jesus Christ! Ow!
I can't understand
why this company went out of business
shortly after this car was made.
You really are holding on seriously there.
[Ricky] Yeah.
It feels like I'm being dragged along
in a tin bath.
That's what this feels like.
Oh, God, you have to turn around
like an owl to see.
There's no mirror in this car.
Jerry, you can't...
There's a mirror here.
I see exactly what I'm doing.
-Oh, Christ.
-[Jerry] What are you worried about?
[Ricky] What am I worried about?
I was thinking maybe for the drive back,
we'd put the top down.
Whatever.
For [bleep] sake.
Oh, come on, Jerry, this is mental.
You don't need to do this.
We're going for coffee, for Christ's sake.
We're not going to diffuse a bomb, right?
There's no need for this.
Even Jack Bauer had an hour, right?
It's turned into a race now.
-It's like a scene from Ronin.
-[laughing]
That was a good laugh to start the day.
My pain and suffering is
for everyone else.
-I fall over for your amusement.
-Yes. Yes. Yes.
-Of course.
-Now you got it.
If someone's laughing with me or at me,
I've done my job.
-That's right.
-Yeah.
[Jerry] The funniest thing
about the nervous passenger is
that you think that that hand
could possibly do something.
I know, yeah.
Jesus Christ! And I'm an atheist.
If you weren't a part of, arguably,
the most successful sitcom of all time...
Why is it arguable? What's the argument?
And who's arguing on the other side,
I wanna know.
If you weren't as successful as you are...
Yeah?
Rich, famous, loved, okay?
Please, go on.
You'd seem a bit like a maniac now.
This is what mad people do,
drive and giggle at people's fear.
"Jerry Seinfeld wants you to do his show.
It's called...
Couple of Comedians Going
for a Drive for Coffee. "Oh, great."
"A man wants to drive you around New York
really fast
in a death machine, laughing."
Look at this, Ricky.
"Welcome to City Island."
-Look at the nautical environment.
-Yeah. Lovely.
-This is great. Come on.
-Yeah.
We've never been here.
You would never ever come here
if it wasn't for me.
No.
I'm giving you a gift.
And I'm going to let you live, as well.
-You've given me the gift of life.
-The gift of life.
Look at this.
I can see sort of an '80s film starting
like this...
Where a writer comes
and then he gets embroiled.
Oh, I love when someone gets embroiled.
I love people getting embroiled.
They shouldn't have been embroiled.
I'm going to a fishing village
and the first thing that happens is...
They get embroiled.
And the reason people get embroiled is,
you never see the embroiling coming.
No.
You never can you see that
I'm about to get embroiled.
[laughing]
If you were in the electric chair,
they would ask you,
"Do you have any last words?"
How could you beat Gary Gilmore?
His last words were, "Let's do it."
-Really?
-Yeah.
I really think the death penalty's
too depressing to even think about.
I don't...
I mean, I don't agree with it.
The state can show
that sort of form of violence.
What about abortion?
Do you agree with that?
Yeah, but that's different, isn't it?
I guess you can just arrange things
the way you like them.
-When you're rich, famous, like you.
-Yeah.
Unlike you,
who's just a guy with an old car
going along the highway,
laughing maniacally
'cause someone feels they're about to die.
I should have said "let's do it"
when I got in this car.
[steam hisses]
[woman] You guys want coffee?
I would love some.
-Just a regular filtered coffee with milk.
-I'll have half and half.
Could I have two yellow eggs
and two egg whites?
What do you mean by that?
You mean four eggs?
-Two yolks and two whites.
-That's just two eggs.
-That's four eggs.
-No.
Two yolks and two whites is two eggs.
What do you mean?
-Two additional whites on top of--
-Right, so four whites and two yolks.
-That's correct.
-Yeah, yeah.
You're like a young king, aren't you?
Things are kept from you.
But you wanna do stuff.
They go,
"He wants to drive around in a car."
And someone said, "Well, just let him
drive around in the car."
-"No, he wants to do it with celebrities."
-"He wants to do it
with some friends he's seen
on the telly."
"Well, get their number."
Would you like some jelly for your toast?
[Ricky] No, I'm fine.
That's great, thank you.
-How was your--
-How were your eggs?
What are these guys doing here?
It's Tuesday...
at 11 o' clock.
Who do you think you are?
You could be a good...
lt's like a man strolling into town going,
"I want to find out what you're doing.
"Just reading the paper."
Make sure he's just read the paper.
See you later.
Although, the older I get...
the more annoyed I am
by what I call...
"other people."
There are people walking around. I'm
going, "Why are you scuffling your feet?
There's no one to pick your feet up.
Don't walk around with your jaw open.
Why do you eat chewing gum like that?
Don't sniff that loudly in public.
Don't spit on the floor."
-Right, you might like Singapore.
-Why do you say that?
-They take care of that stuff.
-Do they really?
-Oh, yeah...
-There's etiquette police
Yeah, you spit your gum on the street,
it's 50 lashes.
Okay, that's going too far, isn't it?
I don't think so.
Not if you really want it clean.
Is that kosher?
You just had bacon.
Slap the cuffs on, judge.
-You got me.
-Listen, I don't make the rules.
You want to, you said before,
you want to be the mayor
that goes around and says,
"Shut your mouth,
stop chewing your gum like that
-and quit shuffling your feet."
-Yeah.
What is the moment in history
that you would like to witness in person?
I'll tell you mine just
to get the conversation rolling.
-Okay.
-Gettysburg Address.
I would like to have been in that crowd
and heard the Gettysburg Address.
Churchill? Would you like to be there
when he's crafting a speech?
How about being in Hitler's bunker
there as he's screaming?
I'd be a bit nervous,
but then, after that car journey,
Hitler doesn't scare me as much.
I'll be honest.
[Ricky] Thank you.
On the last day,
the Russians were advancing.
They were 200 yards down the road.
He married Eva Braun, right?
They had ordered cake and some champagne.
They retired to bed early.
In the morning,
he poisoned her and shot himself.
And the gardener burned the bodies, right?
-Now, say what you will about Hitler...
-Yeah.
But that's a terrible honeymoon, isn't it?
That's a crap honeymoon.
The funniest part of that joke is,
"Say what you will about Hitler."
I'm gonna go to the toilet
and take a Valium for the journey back.
[laughing]
If that's okay.
[engine revving]
[laughing]
Right. Okay.
[laughs]
Jesus, this is like free falling.
I know, it's fantastic.
Don't you feel alive?
Yeah.
-Even if only for a few more minutes.
-Shut up!
[Jerry] I bet you this car looks great.
I'm in heaven.
Do you think we look gay?
The least of my worries.
We're in stylish sunglasses,
we got the top down...
-Yeah.
-in a poncy roadster.
-I think we look gay.
I can just imagine you saying that
when our parachutes didn't open.
And I'm all nervous.
You think we look gay?
It doesn't matter... it doesn't matter.
[laughing]
[Jerry continues laughing]
[Ricky] I'm never gonna do this again.
[Jerry cackles]
[Ricky] Whoa, what the [bleep]